Joseph 'Colin' Lyell

Developer

OVERVIEW

An enthusiastic developer bringing hard work, creativity, attention to detail, and solid programming skills to the table. I have experience with application engineering, full-stack web development and cloud computing using a variety of platforms and architectures.

KEY SKILLS -

Data: SQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Astra DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Languages (desc. Ranked by familiarity): NodeJS, Go, Kotlin, Python, Java, C++

Web: MEAN stack

development, RESTful APIs, Selenium automation

Platforms: GitHub, Docker, AWS, Adobe Creative Cloud, WordPress

Misc: Agile development,

Microsoft SCCM

GITHUB —

github.com/jocoly

EDUCATION —

Indiana University - Southeast New Albany, IN B.S. Computer Science – 2023

University of Louisville Louisville, KY

B.S. Communications – 2019

EXPERIENCE

August 2020 - Present

Intern III • Desktop Operations • Louisville Gas & Electric

- -Writing and maintaining scripts to automate repetitive tasks.
- -Responsible for tech refresh our process for upgrading client hardware for LG&E's corporate office location.
- -Using Windows organizational tools, including Active Directory and SCCM, to maintain inventory and desktop operations asset lifecycle database.

August 2018 - February 2020

Writer/Photographer • The Corydon Democrat • O'Bannon Publishing

- -Implemented publication of two new websites, serving as liaison between developers and editing staff.
- -Coordinated an average of 6-7 editorial projects on a weekly basis without missing tight, often-shifting deadlines.

September 2017 – December 2018

Editor in Chief • The Louisville Cardinal • University of Louisville

-Curated a website and three social media pages while serving as chief executive of the editorial and business operations teams.

PROJECTS

Al Sandbox Discord Bot

- -github.com/jocoly/DiscordAlSandbox
- -A Discord interface for 17 of the most popular open-source AI media models.
- -Locally-hosted Python backend generates images, video, text, and audio from user-provided input.
- -An API facilitates the connection between the NodeJS bot and the servers.

GitHub Auto-Grading Platform

- -csgrader.org
- -Streamlines classroom-scale unit testing for CS assignments.
- -Utilizes microservices powered by AWS cloud tools such as Lambda functions and EC2 machines.